南斯拉夫王国 萨格勒布 1933年12月17日
ZAGREB, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA 17th December 1933.
南斯拉夫国王亚历山大一世，访问萨格勒布的一个省
King Alexander I, Yugoslavia founder, visits Zagreb, one of its provinces.
佩塔尔 · 日瓦科维奇是他的总理，拥有真正的权力
Petar Zhivkovich is his Prime Minister and has the real power.
南斯拉夫王国是当时全世界最高纯度
The Kingdom of Yugoslavia was the producer of the purest
鸦片和海洛因的生产国
and highest quality opium and heroin at this time.
塞尔维亚、克罗地亚、马其顿和波斯尼亚的纷争
Serbian, Croatian, Macedonian and Bosnian
不仅仅是政治问题
clash not only for political issues
也是为了控制非法毒品贸易
but also for the control of illicit drug trafficking.
"图勒"是一个政治性的神秘的社会
The Thule is a political and occult society,
他们的势力范围包括法官
and their sphere of influence includes judges,
警察局长，教授和实业家等等
police chiefs, professors, and industrialists.
哈吉 · 阿尔索夫先生，你的人把一切都搞砸了
Mr. Hadzi Arsov, these guys of yours completely screwed everything up.
- 我的人搞砸了？- 是的
- My guys screwed up? - Yes.
你们没有按计划行事
You did not stick to the plan.
我所做的正是革命…
I did exactly what the revolution...
没有你，没有我们，也没有革命
There are no more you, us, or the revolution.
谁说的？
Who says that?
老板在皮兰等你
The boss is waiting for you in Piran.
带他出去
Take him out.
戈迪纳先生，你赶时间吗？
Mr. Godina, are you in a hurry?
恐怕你得跟我们走一趟了
I'm afraid you'll have to come with us.
南斯拉夫王国 贝尔格莱德 日尔诺夫关卡 阿瓦拉
AVALA, ZHRNOV FORTRESS BELGRADE, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
他回来了
He's back.
什么？
What?
他回来了
He's back.
我回来了
I'M BACK.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第二季 第一集
BLACK SUN SEASON 2 EPISODE 1
新时代报
NEW AGE
卢卡 · 普莱蒂科西奇
LUKA PLETIKOSICH
如果你是来拿离婚协议书的，那你可能来的不是时候
If you came for divorce papers, you didn't pick a very good time.
你很清楚，离婚对我来说和结婚一样重要
Well, you know very well that divorce is as important to me as marriage.
我是来跟卢卡爷爷道别的
I came to say goodbye to grandpa Luka.
你来的真准时
You arrived on time.
过来休息下吧
Let's help ourselves.
我们应该吃点东西，喝点酒
We should eat and drink something.
节哀顺变
My condolences.
谢谢你，亲爱的，来吧
Thank you, honey. Come on.
他没告诉我
He didn't let me know.
我是偶然从报纸上得知的
I found out by accident, from the newspaper.
别担心，他从瑞士回来以后就一直这样
Don't worry. It's like he sold his soul to the devil.
没有你在身边
He has been like that since he returned from Switzerland.
好像丢了魂一样
Without you.
你什么时候来的？
When did you come?
三个月前
Three months ago.
现在回来了，你在做什么工作？
And now, that you're back, what are you doing?
我在医学院教法医学
I teach forensics at medical school.
哦，教授，干得好！
Oh, a professor. Well done!
如果没有你，他永远不会安定下来
He will never settle down without you.
不能没有我，也不能和我在一起
Not without me but not with me, either.
这是波兹达，我的同事
This is Bozidar, my colleague.
我是博雅纳，很高兴见到你
Boyana, nice to meet you.
泽切维奇，我也很高兴见到你
Zecevich, nice to meet you, too.
真的很抱歉，但我们该走了
I really apologize, but we should go.
他们在等我们
They're waiting for us.
阿姨...
Aunt...
我得走了
I have to go.
发生了一些很重要的事情
Something important happened.
感谢你的到来
Thanks for coming.
你知道吗，乔洛维奇，我们现在处于什么样的境地？
Are you aware, Djolovich, what kind of shit are we in now?
最重要的是陛下还活着
The most important thing is that His Majesty is alive.
他还活着是因为乌斯塔莎是白痴，而不是因为我们有能力
He is alive because the Ustasha are idiots, not because we are capable.
我们跟错了线索，但下次...
We followed the wrong trail, but next time...
下一次呢? ！
What next time?!
没有下次了，乔洛维奇
There is no next time, Djolovich.
不是为了你，也不是为了我
Not for you, not for me.
我们还有戈迪纳
We have Godina.
确保他是在我们这边的
Make sure he's good for us.
将军先生
Mr. General.
- 你来这干什么? - 日瓦科维奇先生..
- What the hell do you want? - Mr. Zhivkovich...
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
什么麻烦？
What problem?!
发生了一起谋杀案
There was a murder up there.
在日尔诺夫
At Zhrnov.
来这边
Come.
谁？
Who?
我们的矿工，巴雅克塔瑞维奇
Our miner, Baryaktarevich.
有个阿瓦拉来的疯子闯进去杀了他
Some lunatic from Avala broke in there and killed him.
听我说
Listen to me.
日尔诺夫是你的问题
Zhrnov is your concern,
- 尽你所能去解决 - 是，长官
- solve it however you can. - Yes, sir.
否则，我们就换一个能解决问题的人
Otherwise, we'll find someone who can.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
- 明白了吗？ - 明白
- Understood? - Understood.
我回来了 U.H.
I'M BACK. U.H.
U.H...
U.H.
无名英雄
Unknown hero.
给这个拍张照片，然后让他们拿走
Take a picture of this, so they can take it.
来把这个拿走
Come on, put this away.
是你发现的？
You found him?
是的，黎明时分
Yes. At dawn.
那个疯子把我叫醒，我叫来了其他人
That lunatic woke me up, and I called the others.
他现在在哪儿？
Where is he now?
我们把他关进了格拉夫尼亚卡监狱
We took him to Glavnjacha prison.
你在这里多久了？
And how long have you been here?
两个月
Two months.
这片区域都有人看守吗？
This is all under guard?
这是一项军事任务
This is a military mission.
我们使用炸药作业，平民不允许进入这里
We work with dynamite, civilians are not allowed here.
是啊，那他是怎么到这儿来的？
Yeah. How did he get here then?
我不知道，这个区域都是用铁丝围起来的
I don't know, this is all fenced with wire.
这是唯一的通道，没有人看见他
This is the only passage. Nobody saw him.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
我是凶杀组警察，斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇
Inspector Stanko Pletikosich, homicide.
我是问你在这里做什么？
I'm asking what are you doing here?
你觉得我看起来像在做什么？
What does it look like to you?
这是军事事务，你在这里没有管辖权
This is a military matter. You have no jurisdiction here.
- 这里发生了一起谋杀案 - 是的
- There was a murder here. - Yes.
凶手已经被带到了格拉夫尼亚卡监狱，所以呢？
The killer is taken to Glavnjacha prison, so?
开始干活吧，我们已经延期了
Let us do our job, we're already late.
这么说是真的了? 你要拆毁日尔诺夫？
So it's true? You are demolishing Zhrnov?
你也对这堆石头感到抱歉吗？
Are you sorry for these piles of rocks too?
之前甚至没有人知道它的存在，而现在每个人都在抱怨
No one even knew it existed, and now everyone is whining.
嘿！
Hey!
你要我打电话给你的上司吗？
Do you want me to call your chief?
不需要
No need.
走开
Move.
我们走
Let's go.
意大利 皮兰，南斯拉夫王国边界
PIRAN, ITALY THE KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA BORDER
去把带他过来
Come on, get him there.
我们到底怎么了，阿尔索夫？
What is happening to us, Hadzi Arsov?
你的人在萨格勒布没做什么，是吗？
Your people didn't do much in Zagreb, did they?
你不是很聪明吗？
And you were brilliant?
如果身边都是傻瓜，一个人也做不成什么
One man can't do much if surrounded with fools.
听着，保加利亚人...
Listen, Bulgarian...
美丽的女士，香肠多少钱？
Beautiful young lady, how much for the sausage?
一万第纳尔
Ten thousand dinars.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
去死吧
Go to hell.
我们的营地被关闭了，你听说了吗？
Have you heard of our camps being closed?
是的
Yes.
我认为你最好还是...
I think it would be the best
...低调一段时间
to lay low for a while.
我们已经低调很多年了，还要低调多久了？
We've been laying low for years. How long?!
低调到我们同意
As long as we say so.
鉴于你的罂粟交货时间已经晚得让人无法接受了
Given that your poppy deliveries are unacceptably late,
我恐怕，即使你低调行事，你也有事要做
I'm afraid that, even laid low, you have something to do.
帕维里奇先生，鸦片不是我的工作
Mr. Pavelic, opium is not my job.
我的工作是建立一个独立的马其顿
My job is an independent Macedonia.
鸦片可能不是你的工作，但却是你的责任
It may not be your job, but it is your responsibility.
如果你想要我们或者我们的意大利朋友的支持
If you want our or the support of our Italian friends,
那你就要履行你的责任
then you will fix it.
但这不是我们见面的原因
But that's not why we met.
这是你的临时住址
This is your temporary address.
我们将与你联系并提供进一步的指示
We will contact you with further instructions.
我们保持联系
We'll be in touch.
我希望下次我们能不在如此黑暗的环境见面
I hope next time we'll meet in less dark circumstances.
我诚实善良的哈吉 · 阿尔索夫
My good and honest Hadzi Arsov,
恐怕是我们自己选择了黑暗
I'm afraid we chose that darkness ourselves.
我们会联系你的
We'll contact you.
你要把我永远关在这里吗，又没有任何证据？
Will you keep me here forever, without any evidence?
不会
No.
我们将会通知美国大使馆
We will inform the American embassy
他们已经寻找了7年的
that their famous drug dealer,
著名毒贩
whom they've been looking for seven years,
就在我身边
if I'm not mistaken, is here, with us.
顺便告诉你一声，我们签了州际协议
Just so you know, we signed an interstate agreement.
现在驱逐出境是强制性的
Deportation is now mandatory.
但是还有另外一个选择
But there's another option.
我们准备...
We're ready...
忘记你参与了这次失败的暗杀
to forget your participation in this failed assassination.
- 你没有...-嘿！
- You have no... - Hey!
你的那个交易..
That trade of yours...
绕过了我们的国家
It bypasses our country
而且你今天就可以自由离开这里了
and you can get out of here as a free man today.
一个所有贸易渠道
A free man...
都对他开放的自由人
to whom all channels of trade are open.
我们也可以发展你的业务，戈迪纳
We can also develop that business of yours, Godina.
但我们不在乎
But we don't care.
我们只对乌斯塔沙很感兴趣
We are interested in the Ustashas.
你会为我们工作
You'll work for us,
你会为我们提供情报，并且随时为我服务
you'll give us information and be available to me at any time.
确保哈吉 · 阿尔索夫和你之间的联系终止
Make sure that the communication between Hadzi Arsov
并且那个叫帕维里奇的律师
and you stops and that lawyer Pavelic
和整个乌斯塔莎革命组织分崩离析
and your entire Ustasha family break up with him.
你怎么说？
So?
你好，普莱蒂科西奇，我的兄弟！
Hello, Pletikosa, my man!
看看我买的奶酪，它和白兰地绝配
Take a look at the cheese I bought, it will pair with brandy perfectly.
来喝一杯吧
Come in for a drink.
今天不行，我有很多工作要做
Can't today, I have a lot to of work.
拜托，你知道是谁做的吗？
Oh, come on! Do you know who made it?
- 是他的白兰地吗？ - 当然
- Is it his brandy? - Of course it is.
- 改天吧，我保证 - 我相信你
- Some other time, I promise. - I'll take your word.
- 好的，再见 - 再见
- Okay, bye. - Bye.
哇! 你是真的很想知道现在几点了！
Wow! You really like to know what time it is!
我需要知道！
I need to know!
别唠叨了! 脱下来！
Stop blabbing! Take it off!
- 把外套脱了! - 求你了，不要
- Take off the coat! - Please, don't.
- 你穿了这么多衣服！ - 很冷，不是吗？
- You've put on many clothes! - It's cold, isn't it?
下午好！日沃因，过来
Good afternoon! Zhivoyin, come here.
你想喝点咖啡吗？
Would you like some coffee?
不，谢谢你，如栅
No, thank you, Ruzha.
塔宁不在这里，一切都不一样了
Everything was so different when Tane was here.
请给我一杯咖啡
I would like a coffee, please.
他们把嫌疑犯带来了吗？
Did they bring the suspect?
是的，但他应该直接去精神病院
Yes, but he should be in a psychiatric hospital.
他们移动尸体了吗？
Did they move the corpse?
是的，但是巴比奇还没来上班
Yes, but Babich isn't at work yet.
- 他来了之后告诉我 - 他? 好吧..
- Let me know when he is. - Him? Oh, well...
冲洗照片需要多长时间？
How long it takes you to develop photos?
- 我会尽快的 - 放进报告里
- I'll do it fast. - Put it in the report.
普莱蒂科西奇! 泽切维奇! 过来！
Pletikosich! Zecevich! Come here!
那里发生了什么？
What happened there?
看起来像是宗教仪式谋杀，长官
It looks like a ritual murder, Chief.
所有人今天早上都因为这个事打电话来
Oh, fuck! Everybody called this morning because of that.
还好我们已经有了嫌疑人，他看起来像个疯子
It's good that we have a suspect. He seems like a lunatic.
听着...一定要尽快结案
Listen... Make sure to finish this as soon as possible.
不要乱来，这是军事事务，去吧！
We shouldn't mess with that much, it's a military matter. Come on!
不要再把事情搞复杂了，普莱蒂科西奇！
And don't complicate things again, Pletikosich!
他是怎么绕过整个排的把守
How did he just pass the whole platoon
把那些祭品都放在那里？
and put all those things there?
也许他没那么疯
Maybe he's not that crazy.
拉杰科·卡伊加尼奇
Rajko Kajganic...
是你杀掉了42岁的
Have you killed
尼古拉·巴尔亚克塔雷维奇吗？
Nikola Baryaktarevich, 42 years old?
拉杰科，是你杀了尼古拉·巴尔亚克塔雷维奇吗？
Rajko, have you killed Nikola Baryaktarevich?
是日尔诺夫杀了他，很久以前，它杀了很多人
Zhrnov killed him. Long time ago. It killed many.
他是被回来的人杀死了
He was killed by the one who returned.
谁？
Who?
那个死而复生的人
The one who came back from the dead.
这种情况以前也发生过
It has happened before.
当他被遗忘..
When forgotten...
他回来是为了惩罚
He came back to punish.
你在说什么? ！
What are you talking about?!
我知道是因为我亲眼所见
I know because I've seen it.
你是怎么进入堡垒的？
How did you get into the fort?
通过那扇门
Through the door.
什么门？
What door?
有许多门
Zhrnov has many doors.
你撒谎，只有一个门！
You're lying, there's only one!
这些门看不见，但确实存在，我知道一些
They are not visible, but they exist. I know of some.
他也知道这些门
And he knows them, too.
谁？
Who?
那个回来的人
The one who returned.
- 谁? ! - 吸血鬼
- Who?! - A vampire.
那个已经死了的人！蛇吃了他的眼睛
The one whose name is dead! The snake ate his eyes.
什么吸血鬼？
What Vampire?
- 拉杰科，什么吸血鬼? ! - 我不知道！
- Rajko, what vampire?! - I don't know!
但我知道你迟早会见到他的
But I know you'll see him, sooner or later.
好了
That's enough.
西装不错，老板
Nice suit, boss.
昨天从布达佩斯送来的
It arrived yesterday, from Budapest.
走吧，孩子们！
Come on, boys! Come on!
法国人把订单增加了一倍！要为圣诞节准备新的货物！
The French doubled the order! The new cargo goes for Christmas!
太好了，我们要用火车送吗？
Oh, nice. We're sending it by train?
是的，一如既往，我们走！
Yes, as always. Let's go!
这是什么? ！
What is this?!
你为什么把它放在马路中间？
Why did you put it in the middle of the street?
不是”它”，这是我爷爷斯托亚丁
It's not "it" but my grandpa Stojadin.
五场战争的参与者
Participant of five wars.
是彼得国王我也不在乎！
I don't care even if it's The King Peter!
停下，神父！
Cut it, priest!
我不能停，这是为了灵魂的安宁
I can't, this is for the peace of the soul.
快挪走！
Move it!
你想变成为了你灵魂的安宁吗? ！
Would you like it to be for the peace of your soul?!
如果我们不想挪它呢？
What if we don't want to move it?
- 如果你不想？ - 是的
- If you don't want? - Yes.
那么...
Well, then...
等等，等等... 冷静点，孩子们！
Wait, wait.. Calm down, boys!
我们不想惹麻烦！也不想看到谁的脑浆流出来
We don't want trouble! Let's not burn some brains out!
放下枪，这样我就不用为你的灵魂唱歌了！
Throw that shit so I don't sing for your soul now!
别动！
Don't move!
哦，米兰！
Oh, Milan!
我就知道是你！
I knew it was you!
维利加！
Veriga!
你升级了
You've advanced.
当有人背叛时，我就会接替他们的位置
When someone betrays, I advance to their place.
你是在告诉我什么狗屁荣誉吗？
Are you telling me some shit about honour?
你穿那套衣服很好看
That suit looks good on you.
谁能比裁缝更了解它呢？
Who would know it better than a tailor?
迪塞尔，过来
Diesel, come here.
你喜欢这个男人的西装吗？
Do you like this man's suit?
- 真的很白 - 谁想...斯马！
- It's pretty white. - Who would like to... Sima!
- 你想把它脱下来吗？- 当然，老板
- Would you like to take it off? - Of course, boss.
斯马会脱的
Sima will do it,
但是当他脱掉衣服的时候，会感到很兴奋
but when he takes off the clothes, he's really turned on.
那可能会很糟糕
It could be pretty fucked.
你要知道，修道士会记住这件事的
Just so you know, the Monk will remember this.
他也只能记住了
That's all he can.
脱下来！
Take it off!
他的手指被割掉了
His finger is cut.
这个人已经死了超过24小时
This man has been dead for more than 24 hours.
所以他是被杀之后被带到阿瓦拉？
So he was killed and then brought to Avala?
尸体上到处都是土壤的痕迹
Traces of loam all over the body,
在他头上，手上...
on his head, hands...
仿佛他们拖着他穿过了沼泽
As if they had dragged him through a swamp.
所以你是在阿瓦拉找到他的，在日尔诺夫附近？
So you found him in Avala, near Zhrnov?
没错
That's right.
在无名英雄纪念碑前
In front of the monument to the Unknown Hero.
倒也不是无名
Well, he's not unknown.
奥地利人可能不知道他
He may be unknown to the Austrians,
是他们把他埋了
they buried him.
- 但我们知道他是谁 - 什么意思？
- We know who he is. - What do you mean?
伊萨科维奇教授，愿他安息
Professor Isakovic, may he rest in peace,
二十世纪二十年代，他在战后负责挖掘尸体
he did the exhumation, after the war, in the 1920s.
我刚来到这里工作
I just came here then and started working.
是谁被埋在那里？
Who is buried there?
一个孩子，他的家人被杀了
A child. His family was killed.
真是个悲惨的故事，一定在我们的档案里
Sad story. It must be somewhere in our archives.
但我更感兴趣的是这是什么？
But I'm more interested in what this is.
我不明白
I don't understand this.
疤痕组织
Scarred tissue.
不，这个... 围着它
No, this... around it.
它看起来像一张帆
It looks like a sail.
什么帆？这孩子是谁？
What sail?! Who is this kid?!
这看起来更像是一个十字架
This looks more like a cross.
该死，和我一起工作的人..
Damn, whom I'm working with...
我会死在这里
I will die in here.
巴比奇，还有什么线索？
Babich, what else do we have?
凶手显然很熟练使用刀具
The killer was obviously very skilled with the knife.
但这些不是刀伤
But these are not knife wounds.
要我说这看起来像是战争的伤口
To me, it looks like war wounds.
如果不是刀或手术刀，那会是什么呢？
If it's not a knife or a scalpel, what could it be?
想想看，胖子! 战争还会有什么伤？
Well, think about it, fatty! What could be from the war?
刺刀！
A bayonet!
我会把它交给政府
I'll take it to the municipality.
你会得到帮助的
You will get help.
你只需要有点耐心
You just have to be a bit patient.
两三个星期
Two or three weeks.
好吧，我这辈子都在受苦，所以我可以再受点苦
Okay, I suffer my whole life, so I can suffer a little more.
圣诞节过后再来，我会处理好的
Come after Christmas, and I'll take care of it.
上帝保佑你，迪米特里耶维奇先生
God bless you, Mr. Dimitriyevich.
这与上帝无关
God has nothing to do with it.
非常感谢
Thanks a lot.
- 下午好，先生 - 下午好
- Good afternoon, sir. - Good afternoon.
用力拉！
Pull harder!
使劲拉，该死的！
Pull harder, God damn you!
- 长官！ - 我已经不是长官了
- Chief! - I'm not a chief, anymore.
我去看医生，不得不付钱
I went to the doctor and had to pay.
你为什么不出示我给你的收据？
Why didn't you show the receipt I gave you?
去你的收据！
Fuck your receipt!
我一直在等它，但还是得付钱！
I've been waiting for it and still had to pay!
那你至少健康了？
Are you healthy at least?
去他妈的健康！
Fuck health when it costs!
去你妈的！
Oh, fuck you, too!
- 这个，安塔叔叔！ - 那是什么？
- Here it is, Uncle Anta! - What's that?
我们不是要去穿土耳其人
We are not going to impale the Turks,
而是要把猪叉在烤肉架上！
but to put the pig on the spit!
- 怎么了？ - 你可真是笨手笨脚！
- What's wrong with it? - You have two left hands!
我来剪吧，没问题
I'll cut it, no problem.
迪米特里耶维奇，他们会拆掉这里吗？
Dimitriyevich, will they demolish this?
即使他们拆掉了你这个破房子，也不会是一件遗憾的事
Even if they demolished this barrack of yours, it wouldn't be a pity.
你会在城市的另一个地方做同样的梦
You would make the same one, in another part of town.
不可能！只有一个亚塔汉贫民窟
No way! Nothing like the Yataghan slum!
忘记的亚塔汉贫民窟吧
Karadjordje's moat. Forget the Yataghan slum.
快点，叫这些人在这里签名
Come on, call these people to put their signatures here.
那是什么？
What's that?
联名抗议书，反对拆迁
The remonstrance. People against demolition.
- 我会把它交给市政局 - 什么？
- I'll take it to the municipality. - What?
抗议书，人民反对拆迁
The remonstrance, people against demolition.
- 过来签字 - 他们才不在乎呢！
- Come here to sign. - They don't give a fuck about that!
过来，过来签字
Come, come here to sign.
他不会签，他是文盲
He can't, he's illiterate.
看看他！
Look at him!
现在会书法了，但是不会磨木桩
Now he knows calligraphy, but he can't sharpen a stake.
你们都应该签字
All of you should sign.
否则，这里就再也没有亚塔汉贫民窟
Otherwise, there's no Yataghan slum.
下午好，米里奇先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Mirich.
哦，你来了
Oh, you've arrived.
是的，但是很不幸，我没有多少时间
Yes. But, unfortunately, I don't have much time.
萨夫科维奇先生，你真的想让我
Mr. Savkovich, do you really want me
结束与永恒的的邂逅吗？
to end my encounter with eternity?
我想你们的会面
I think it would be good to pause your encounter
暂停一段时间会比较好
with eternity for a while.
非常乐意
With great pleasure.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
所有人都出去！
Everyone, out!
先生们，来谈正事了
Gentlemen, I am at your disposal. Please.
我们的朋友又看了一遍计划，终于满意了
Our friends looked at the plans again and were finally satisfied.
是时候了
Well, it was about time.
米里奇先生，西门子和工厂
Mr. Mirich, the Siemens and Telefunken industrial plants
比你的仓库要复杂一点
are a little more complicated than your warehouses.
特别是这个有敏感的目的的项目
Especially this one. With such a sensitive purpose.
你是说间谍活动？
You mean espionage?
这是最好的位置，相信我
This is the best location, trust me.
有时候我听不懂你的幽默
Sometimes I don't understand your humour.
告诉我，你最后对这个地方满意吗
Tell me, are you finally satisfied with the location
你的印刷厂吗？
of your printing house?
- 是的 - 我也是
- Yes, I am. - Me, too.
那么告诉你的记者们少挖一点也不是坏事
Then it wouldn't be bad to tell your journalists to sniff a little less
因为他们让我很紧张
around Prizad because they get on my nerves.
因为如果我作为一个受人尊敬的公民
Because if I, as a respectable citizen,
对此无能为力
cannot do anything about it,
那么你作为“新时代”的拥有者，绝对可以
then you, as the owner of "New Age", definitely can.
我不太担心这个问题
I wouldn't worry too much about that.
与其遮遮掩掩，不如直接控制媒体
It's better to write under control, than to sweep things under the rug.
我们称之为“新闻自由”
We call it "freedom of the press".
不会有任何问题
There will be no problems.
最好没有
Well, there better be none.
因为我会用不同的方式解决问题
Because I solve my problems in a different way.
幸运的是，我们在这里
Fortunately, we are here.
就是为了阻止你这样做
To stop you from doing so.
- 生意怎么样? - 很好
- How's the business? - Excellent.
银行已经为转账做好了一切准备
The bank has prepared everything for transfers,
首次付款已经开始
the first payments have started,
我们只是在等待日尔诺夫事件的最终结果
we are just waiting for the matter around Zhrnov to finally end.
嘿，别担心日尔诺夫，有人会解决的
Hey, don't you worry about Zhrnov, there is someone to think about it.
这些都是我们正在解决的小问题
These are some small problems that we are just solving,
一切都没问题的，我保证
everything will be fine, I guarantee it.
法官，许可证怎么样了？
Judge, what about permits?
我们正在努力
We're working on it.
法官大人，你已经为此努力了两个月了
Your Honour, you have been working on this for two months now.
只有这样，才能让一切在法律上变得无懈可击
That's the only way to make everything go painlessly, legally.
我和你在亚塔汉贫民窟的人有联系
I'm in touch with your man from Yataghan Slum.
如果你让我做，许可证早就有了
If you had let me do it, you would already have permits.
先生们...
Gentlemen...
亚塔汗贫民窟实际上是这个城市的一个贫民窟
The Yataghan slum is really a slum of this city.
这个项目将使贝尔格莱德成为欧洲的一部分
And this project should make Belgrade a part of Europe.
最现代化的工厂，最现代化的住宅区..
The most modern factories, the most modern residential areas...
先生们，我们已经为此努力了很多年
Gentlemen, we've been working on this for years.
- 我没有耐心了 - 找到它！
- I have no more patience. - Find it!
否则，就不会有项目
Otherwise, there will be no project.
我们的朋友也是这么想的，明白吗？
That's what our friends think, too. Is that clear?
米里奇先生，有位先生来了
Mr. Mirich, the gentleman is here.
维利加
Veriga.
那又怎样？
So?
你最好自己看看
You better see for yourself.
又是亚塔汉那些人？
The Yataghans again?
"蛇头一定要跺两次才安心"
"A snake's head should definitely be stomped twice."
这到底是怎么回事！
What the hell this was?!
这些床单挂在这弄得好像我们在波兰医院一样? ！
Why are these sheets here like we're in a Polish hospital?!
我跟她们说过，但她们不听
I've told them but they wouldn't listen.
什么都不用说，把这些东西都扔掉！
No need to tell anything, just throw all of the shit away!
不要! 我们已经洗了一上午了！
Don't! We've been washing it all morning!
等德拉吉尼亚看到你的时候，我们都完了！
When Draginya sees you, we're all screwed!
别跟我喊，开始做你擅长的事吧！
Stop yelling and start doing what you know!
来吧，都拿到酒吧去
Come on! Take it all to the bar.
米兰！
Milan!
你喊什么? ！
Why are you yelling?!
让孩子们做体面的工作! 明白了吗？
Let the kids do an honest job! Is that clear?
好的，中士
As you say, Sergeant.
解散
Dismissed.
体面个屁！
Honest job, my ass!
她们被干一次赚的钱比洗一个月衣服还多！
They earn more for one bonk than a month of washing!
这就是我想说的，老板，但是德拉吉尼亚一直在找麻烦
That's what I'm saying, boss, but Draginya is making an issue of it.
别管德拉吉尼亚! 她是我的朋友！
Leave Draginya alone! She's my pal!
好吧
Okay.
- 嘿儿子！ - 什么事妈妈？
- Hey, son! - Yes, Mum?
- 那是什么？ - 一套新西装
- What's that?! - A new suit.
什么新西装？
What new suit?!
白色的
A white one.
脱下来! 哦，上帝，那个米兰..
Take it off! Oh, God, that Milan...
- 等等，这布料不错 - 布达佩斯的
- Wait, this fabric is good! - From Budapest.
布达佩斯? 我们回家吧
Budapest? Let's go home.
米兰！
Milan!
我们不是说好不带我儿子的吗？
Didn't we agree to leave my son alone?
据我所知，你让他去打拳击
As far as I remember, you let him box.
但我没让他偷东西
But I didn't let him steal.
如果你再带他去偷东西
If you take him to steal again,
你就要对付我了，明白吗？
you'll be dealing with me. Clear?
好的
Yes.
现在让你的白痴小弟们带一箱白兰地到我家来
Now tell your idiots to bring a box of cognac to my house.
哦，迪米特里耶维奇！
Oh, Dimitriyevich!
你在干什么? 涂鸦吗？
What are you doing? Scribbling something?
你想念你的办公室吗？
Do you miss your office?
我得养家糊口
I have to make a living.
我很清楚你是怎么谋生的，迪米特里耶维奇
I know very well how you make a living, Dimitriyevich.
我做的是体面的工作，就像你一样
I do an honest job, just like you.
是的，非常体面
Yeah, it's very honest.
你打算什么时候带我进你的扑克牌桌？
When are you going to put me in that poker of yours?
对不起，已经满了，下次吧
I'm sorry, but it's filled. Another time.
你他妈的一点都不抱歉，你总是这么跟我说
You're not fucking sorry. You always tell me the same.
该死，以前还不错，是吧？
Damn it, it used to be good, huh?
以前你逮捕我们的时候
It used to be good when you arrested us.
我只是在做我的工作
I was doing my job.
你做了政客们让你做的事
You did what the politicians told you to do.
而那些不能给你下命令的人
And those who couldn't give you any orders,
会给你现金
they gave some cash.
但是现在，他们都耍了你！
But now, all of them screwed you over!
离开格拉夫尼亚卡监狱是我的决定
It was my decision to leave Glavnjacha prison.
这是我的选择
It was my choice.
你可以把这些话告诉别人！
You can tell that shit to someone else!
你逃离了阿里姆皮耶，所以他才没有阉了你！
You ran away from Alimpiye, so he wouldn't cut off your dick!
看看这一切是如何发生的？
See how it all comes to its own place?
现在你和我在一起是最安全的
You're safest with me now.
阿里姆皮耶把我们逼入绝境
Alimpiye cornered us.
而你抢劫了他
And you robbed him.
你认为那些上诉和投诉
And you think that those appeals and complaints
可以帮助你安抚那些
will help you appease those municipal shitheads
抓着他蛋蛋的混蛋政客！
that he's holding by the balls?!
这个州是有法律的
There are laws in the state.
这里只有一条法律,
There's only one law here,
就是弱肉强食
and it's the law of the strongest.
没错，这就是问题所在
True. That's the problem.
你不是最强的
You're not the strongest.
毕竟，它是神圣的！
After all, it is sacred!
- 拜托，日尔诺夫才不神圣！ - 什么意思？
- Come on, Zhrnov isn't sacred! - What do you mean?!
那是拉撒路皇帝建造的！
The Emperor Lazarus built it!
暴君斯特凡！
Despot Stefan!
子承父业
Father started and son finished it.
不完全是那样的
It wasn't exactly like that.
- 不是吗? ! - 不，不，日尔诺夫更古老
- It isn't?! - No, no. Zhrnov is older.
它是罗马人建造的
It was built by the Romans.
拉撒路和暴君斯特凡重建了它
Lazarus and Despot rebuilt it.
后来被土耳其人占领
And then it was occupied by the Turks,
把匈牙利人隔在贝尔格莱德，因此得名阿瓦拉
to keep the Hungarians in Belgrade, hence the name Avala.
它在阿拉伯语中的意思是“一个障碍”
It means "an obstacle" in Arabic.
村民们说地下隧道里什么都有
The villagers say there is everything in the underground tunnels.
老式的矿井
Those are old, mining shafts.
不管是什么，他们都不该碰它！
Whatever it is, they shouldn't have touched it!
会出问题的！
Something will go wrong!
日沃因，你在说什么？
Zhivoyin, what are you talking about?
- 关于日尔诺夫 - 一个神圣的地方！
- About Zhrnov. - A sacred place!
别说了，朱巴，你发现什么了吗？
Stop it. Ljuba, have you found something?
- 是的，给你看看 - 去办公室
- I have, let's take a look. - In the office.
我跟没跟你说过工作时不准喝白兰地！
What did I tell you about brandy at work?!
我们还要再吵吗？
Do we have to argue again?
- 不用，探长 - 我也这么认为
- No, inspector. - I think so, too.
收起来
Put it away.
该死，塔尼，你把我们留给了... 干杯！
Damn, Tane, whom you left us with... Cheers!
“1915年，德国人向阿瓦拉进军
"In 1915, Germans marched on Avala
”仿佛整个帝国的命运都取决于此
"as if the fate of the empire depended on it.
“一个男孩站在栏杆上
"A boy was standing on the parapet.
“一个男孩，对抗整个帝国
"One boy, against the whole empire.
“一颗手榴弹击中了他，撕裂了他的心
"A grenade hit him, ripping his heart out.
“当奥地利人到达阿瓦拉顶端时
"When the Austrians reached the top of Avala,
”他们意识到，他们是在和一个孩子作战
"they realized that they were fighting even against children.
”他们以崇高的敬意埋葬了他
"They buried him with all honours,
“在一个木质十字架上，他们用德语写道:
"on a wooden cross, they wrote in German:
“这里躺着一位不知名的塞尔维亚英雄”
"'Here lies an unknown Serbian hero.'
“他们把手榴弹当作床头板
"They put the grenade as a headboard,
”他的头枕在钢铁上
"his head was resting on the steel.
作为无名英雄的枕头”
A pillow for an unknown hero."
这是一篇非常感人的文章
That's a very touching text.
是的
It is.
你认为这是真的吗？
Do you think it's true?
在每一个传说中都有一丝真理
In every legend there's a grain of truth.
我不知道，在那些年里，一切都是在虚幻中写成的
I don't know, in those years everything was written in ecstasy.
关于挖掘尸体你有什么发现？
What did you find about the exhumation?
- 没什么 - 什么意思？
- Nothing. - What do you mean?
当年我们搬迁档案馆的时候
Back then, when we moved the archive,
我们把文件弄混了
we mixed up the documentation a bit.
把文件搞混了? ！
You mixed the documentation?!
弄混了好几个年份
Well, we are missing some years,
但我敢发誓我们有一个完整的1921年档案
but I could swear we had a full 1921.
如果我没有完整的档案，我要怎么工作？
How could I work if I don't have a tidy archive?
好的，我尽快整理
Okay, I'm working on it.
如果有发现我会告诉你的
I'll let you know if I find something.
好吧
Okay.
为什么他说自己是一个无名英雄？
Why does he sign himself as an unknown hero?
“我回来了”
"I'm back."
这意味着什么？
What does it mean?
所以，阿尔索夫应该为这一切负责？
So, Hadzi Arsov is to blame for everything?
我并不是要让我的人逃避责任
I am not trying to keep my people out of their responsibility.
但即使一切顺利
But even if it went like a clockwork,
我们还是会因为那个马其顿傻瓜而倒霉
we would still be screwed because of that Macedonian fool.
他什么事都自己做
He does everything on his own.
因为他，我差点进了监狱
I've almost ended up in prison because of him.
更不用说他的白痴手下
Not to mention that his idiots are late
连续两个月延期交付鸦片
with delivering poppies for two months.
塞尔维亚警察把他们逼到角落，他们什么也做不了
Serbian police cornered them, they can't do anything.
好吧，好吧
Okay, okay.
别担心，一切都会好的
Don't worry, everything will be fixed.
现在意大利人把我们打败了
Now that the Italians have knocked us out,
我们所能做的就是依靠奇迹
all we can do is rely on a miracle.
我现在向你介绍一位克罗地亚妇女
I will now introduce you to one of our Croatian women.
她会把我们和那个奇迹联系起来
She will connect us with that miracle.
德国的奇迹！
A German miracle!
这是唯一的救赎
That's the only salvation.
请到艺术馆
To the Museum of Art, please.
世界正在发生巨大的变化
The world is changing dramatically.
我坚信经过多年的混乱
I firmly believe that after years of chaos,
欧洲将再次恢复秩序与和平
order and peace will reign in Europe again.
新的欧洲也会有全新的艺术品诞生
The new Europe will also have new art.
崭新的、更好的艺术
It is the art of a new, better man.
在最近成立的帝国文化厅的帮助下
And with the help of a recently established Reich Chamber of Culture,
我们将为新画廊献上一份礼物
we will present a gift to your new art gallery.
这是我妻子送给维也纳的礼物
A gift from my wonderful wife to the city of Vienna.
玛雅，请
Maya, please.
就几句话
Just a few words.
作为一个在维也纳找到幸福的南斯拉夫人
As a Yugoslav who found her happiness in Vienna,
我深信不疑
I am deeply convinced
我们应该抛开过去
that we should leave the past behind
一起面向未来
and that we should all turn to the future together.
女士们先生们，我向你们介绍勇士阿诺 · 布莱克！
Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you the warrior Arno Brecker!
干杯！
Cheers!
嗯，进行得很顺利
Well, this went great.
我担心不会有很多人
I was afraid there wouldn't be many people.
说到艺术，我们是一个国家
When it comes to art, we are one country.
- 我们是一个国家 - 什么意思？
- We are one country. - What do you mean?
你很快就会明白的，亲爱的
You will see, dear, I hope, very soon.
哦，帕夫利克先生，你在这儿啊！
Oh, Mr. Pavelic. There you are!
我的荣幸！
My respect!
你可以用塞尔维亚语和我说话
You can talk to me in Serbian.
当然
Of course.
克劳斯，这就是我跟你说过的那位先生
Klaus, that's the gentleman I told you about.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
从喜悦中获得力量
Strength through joy.
这可以成为新艺术的座右铭！
That can be the motto of new art!
我更喜欢: 从喜悦中获得媚俗
I would rather say: Kitsch through joy.
这个雕塑不是我选的，是我丈夫选的
I did not choose this sculpture. My husband did.
图勒的领导人不应该说这样的话
One of the leaders of Tula should not talk like that.
我想见你很久了
I've wanted to meet you for a long time.
玛丽亚 · 奥西奇，很高兴见到你
Maria Orsich, nice to meet you.
塞尔维亚王子旅馆
HOTEL SERBIAN PRINCE
给你
Here you go.
- 下午好 - 下午好
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon.
- 你会说法语吗？ - 会一点，有什么可以帮到您吗？
- Do you speak French? - A bit. Can I help you?
我预订了今晚和明天的房间
I have a room reserved, for tonight and tomorrow.
- 您的名字？ - 诺维奇 · 利奥波德
- Your name? - Nowicki Leopold.
等一下
A moment.
- 哦，诺维奇伯爵 - 没错
- Of course, Count Nowicki. - That's right.
- 请填写您的详细信息 - 谢谢
- Please enter your details. - Thanks.
- 您的钥匙 - 谢谢，先生
- Your key. - Thank you, sir.
先生... 有位先生在酒吧等你
Sir... A gentleman is waiting for you at the bar.
我们会照顾好行李的
We'll take care of the luggage.
是我，他来了
It's me. He's arrived.
我听说你很多年了，我们还没见过面
I've been hearing about you for years, and we haven't met.
如果你在维也纳多待一段时间
If you had spent more time in Vienna,
我们很久以前就该见面了
we would have met a long time ago.
是的，但是这里太无聊了
Yes, but it's so boring here.
这个城市就像一个迷人的女人
This city is like an attractive woman.
逐渐揭开神秘的面纱
You discover the secrets gradually.
这就是魅力所在，不是吗？
That's the charm, isn't it?
更不用说维也纳现在是欧洲的中心
Not to mention that Vienna is the centre of Europe now.
即使在战争失败、帝国瓦解之后？
Even after it lost the war and her empire fell apart?
就像恋爱一样，亲爱的
It's like being in love, my dear.
战争永远不会结束
The war never ends.
失败是暂时的，就像胜利一样
The losses are temporary, just like the victories.
像你这么漂亮的女人应该知道这一点
A beautiful woman like you should know that.
你有烟吗？
Do you have a cigarette?
这就是为什么我最好待在贝尔格莱德
That's why it's better for me to stick to my Belgrade.
那么既然你在那边
Well, while you're sticking to it,
可以照顾一下我们的组织
you could take some care of our organization
并与总部协调工作
and coordinate its work with the headquarters.
可惜你明天就要走了
Too bad you're leaving tomorrow,
不然我可以告诉你这个城市隐藏着什么秘密
I'd show you what secrets this city hides.
玛雅
Maya.
我丈夫
My husband.
克劳斯
Klaus.
下午好
Good afternoon.
是的，你明天有个会议
And yes, you have a meeting tomorrow.
我们明天一早就走
We're leaving tomorrow, early.
10点的飞机
You have a plane at 10.
7点到这个地址
And at 7, be at this address.
我不必强调这有多重要
I don't have to stress how important that is.
这个女人想干什么？
What is this woman looking for here?
你认识她，对吧？
You know her, don't you?
正是因为我认识她，我才不想见到她
Precisely because I know her I don't want to see her.
如果我不得不忍受这些原始人
If I have to put up with those primitives
还有柏林的精神病患者
and psychopaths in Berlin,
但这并不意味着我还要忍受她
that doesn't mean I have to put up with her,
尤其是不能当她的邮递员
and especially not to be her postman.
得了吧！
Come on!
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
诺维基伯爵... 欢迎
Count Nowicki... Welcome.
- 拉贾奇基，很高兴见到你 - 很高兴见到你
- Rajachki, nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- 想喝点什么吗？- 很好
- Would you like a drink? - With pleasure.
服务员！
Waiter!
我们直接聊正事吧，我很累了
If we can get to the point right away, I'm very tired.
如你所愿
As you wish.
明天晚上10点我会在广场等你
Tomorrow night, I'll be waiting for you in the square at 10 pm.
走路过去，离旅馆很近
Come on foot, it's close to the hotel.
- 我的联系人是你吗？- 不是
- Will my contact be with you? - No.
我带你去见他的地方
I'll take you to the place where you'll meet him.
穿着庄重一些，这是新年前夜
Dress solemnly, it's the New Year's Eve.
我怎么才能找到他？
How will I find him?
在入口处介绍一下自己，一切都安排好了
Introduce yourself at the entrance, everything is organized.
你1月1日去拜访国王？
Your visit to the king on January 1st?
计划都没有改变？
Nothing has changed there?
没有，是一月一号十点,
No. The visit is on the first of January at ten,
然后我要和我们的兄弟见面对吧？
and then I have a meeting with our brother, right?
没错
That's right.
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
希望你不会太久
I hope you won't be long.
但愿如此
I hope so.
亲爱的达维多维奇夫人，很高兴见到你
Dear Mrs. Davidovich. I'm so glad to see you.
我知道你赶时间，我不会占用太长时间
I know you're travelling soon, we won't be long.
把这封信交给利诺维奇·利奥波德伯爵
You will hand over this letter to Count Leopold Nowicki.
他将和你同时在贝尔格莱德
He will be in Belgrade at the same time as you.
恐怕我不认识伯爵
I'm afraid I don't know the count.
别担心，他会找到你的
Leopold Nowicki. Don't worry, he'll find you.
这件事对我们的组织至关重要
The matter is of the utmost importance to our order.
这个信息不应落入他人之手
At no cost should this message fall into the wrong hands.
这就是为什么我把这个极其重要的任务托付给你
That's why I entrust you with this extremely important task.
我很荣幸
I'm flattered.
你应该感到荣幸
And you should be.
就这些了，达维多维奇女士
That would be all, Ms. Davidovich,
我不会再耽搁你了
I will not detain you anymore.
旅途愉快
Have a nice trip.
- 再见 - 再见
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
我们谈完了
We're done.
你还认为我们应该把
Do you still think that we should entrust
如此重要的任务委托给贝尔格莱德组织吗？
such an important task to a Belgrade organization?
是的，一切都在控制之中
Yes. It's under control.
但你不应该找达维多维奇女士
But you shouldn't have interfered with Ms. Davidovich.
你觉得我们怎么才能绕过她？
And how did you think we could get around her?
一如既往
As always.
她仍然是南斯拉夫图勒组织的负责人
She is still the head of the Yugoslav Thule Society.
不管怎样，我不相信她
Anyway. I don't trust her.
凭什么? 凭你的直觉？
Based on what? Your intuitions?
我的直觉从未让我失望
My intuition never let me down.
在你找到更有力的证据之前
Until you find a stronger argument,
我们将遵守组织的规则
we will follow the rules of our order.
我希望你知道你在做什么
I hope you know what you are doing.
如果出了什么差错，有人可能会陷入麻烦
If something goes wrong, someone could get in trouble.
很快就见分晓了，不是吗？
We'll see very soon, won't we?
那啤酒是给猪喝的，不是给你喝的! 该死！
That beer is for the pig, not for you! Damn!
滴一滴！
Drizzle it!
我正在滴！
I'm doing it!
转过来，下面烧焦了！
Turn it around, it's burned!
没有焦，只是在泥里打滚时弄脏了
It didn't burn, it got dirty when it rolled in the mud.
拜托，世界上没有脏猪这种东西
Come on, there's no such thing as a dirty pig.
穿过这片泥泞，一直走到酒吧
Keep straight to the bar, through this mud.
- 这是什么? ! - 好货
- What's this?! - Fine goods.
去你的，女人不是货物！
Damn you, women aren't pieces of meat!
我们的阴道配不上你了
Our cunt doesn't suit you anymore,
但是中心来的的那些就配得上？
but the ones from the centre?!
谁要干你？
Who's gonna fuck you?
好心的先生们今晚会来，这是为他们准备的
Nice gentlemen are coming tonight, it's for them.
去你妈的，混蛋! 你真丢脸! 去死吧！
Fuck you, motherfucker! Shame on you! Go to hell!
迪塞尔，过来拿手提箱！
Diesel, come here to take the suitcase!
好一对大奶奶！我能摸摸吗？
Look at those tits! Can I touch them?
好啊
Yes.
滚! 你有钱吗？
Get outta here! Do you have money?
给钱才能摸
If you do, you can touch them.
- 等我今晚赢了钱 - 等你赢了？
- As soon as I win tonight. - As soon as you win?
- 走开！ - 哦，警长先生，下午好！
- Go away! - Oh, Mr. Chief, good afternoon!
你是来逮捕我的吗？
Did you come to arrest me?
不是，亲爱的，我只是想见见你
No, sweetie. Just wanted to see you.
嘿，孩子! 把她带走！
Hey, kid! Take her away!
- 发生什么事了？ - 快走
- What happened? - Go, go.
兰卡! 过来，我有个任务给你！
Ranka! Come here, I have a task for you!
只是别让我再搓任何东西，看看我的手！
Just don't make me rub anything again, look at my hands!
不，不，你会得到丰厚的报酬
No, no. You'll be well paid.
我会给你一些钱让你穿得更好
I'll give you some money to dress better.
迪米特里耶维奇，你要带她去哪里？
Dimitriyevich, where are you taking her?
你管我呢？
Why do you care?
裁缝叫我多带些人过来
Tailor told me to bring reinforcements,
而你却在带人走
and you break up my base.
告诉裁缝，从现在开始兰卡为我工作
Tell the Tailor that Ranka works for me from now on.
该死！从你来亚塔汉贫民窟的那天！
Damn the day you came to Yataghan slum!
去你的，吉普赛混蛋! 走开！
Fuck you, gypsy jerk! Go away!
来吧，淋一下！
Come on, drizzle it!
哦，拜托! 你也是? ! 你是想吃猪肉干吗? ！
Oh, come on! You too?! Wanna eat dry pig?!
下午好
Good afternoon.
嘿！别管那头猪，过来！
Hey! Fuck that pig, come here!
给我！
Gimme that!
丹兹米，你也是! 来！
Dezim, you too! Come!
给你一半
A half for you.
还有吗? 没有了吗? 一半给你
Have more? No? And half for you.
你要把那些纸给人们
You will give people those papers,
他们会给你钱
and they will give you money.
真的？就这几张破纸？
Really? For the paper?!
这就是所谓的赌博
It's called betting.
如果你这么说的话
If you say so.
听着，枪支贫民窟的人更强，他应该能赢
Look, the Gun Boy is better, stronger, he should win.
什么? ! 我们的人要踢他的屁股！
What?! Our boy is gonna kick his ass!
等等，一直这么说
Wait. Just keep saying that
另一个更好！
the other guy is better!
我们的人会像打租来的骡子一样打他！
Our boy is gonna beat him like a rented mule!
闭嘴！
Stop it!
每个人都应该把赌注押在另一个人身上！
Everyone should bet on the other guy!
但为什么呢？
But why?
这样我们就赚到更多的钱！
So we get more money!
该死！
Damn!
我们会赚到更多的钱！
We'll get more money!
- 好吧，我不傻 - 该死的！
- Okay, I'm not stupid. - God damn you!
就是这样，先生们! 就算是警察也有良心！
That's it, gentlemen! Even police have a heart!
我们也应该庆祝新年
We should celebrate the New Year, too.
来吧! 干杯！
Come on! Cheers!
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
干杯！
Cheers!
晚餐准备好了吗？
Is the dinner ready?
如栅，你做了白菜卷了吗？
Ruzha, have you made the sarma?
没做，长官
No, Chief.
你还在等什么? 快点！
What are you waiting for? Come on!
- 大家六点见！- 好的！
- See you everyone at six! - Deal!
下午好，长官
Good afternoon, Chief.
普莱蒂科西奇，你也去参加
Pletikosich, I would like to see you there, too.
好的，长官，到办公室来
Okay, Chief. Come to the office.
再喝一杯就结束了！
One more drink and that's it!
- 来吧! - 干杯！
- Come on! - Cheers!
过来
Come here.
看看这个
Take a look.
看起来像个入口
It looks like an entrance.
在我看来，它更像是一个影子
It looks more like a shadow to me.
对我来说，它看起来像一个入口
To me, it looks like an entrance.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我们今晚去普尔沙吗？
Are we going to Prsha tonight?
- 是的 - 探长！
- Yes. - Inspector!
我调查了那个疯子拉杰科，没什么发现
I checked on that crazy Rajko and there's not much.
他完成了学业，没有家庭，参加过战争
He finished teacher's school, no family, he was at war...
那些年每个人都参加了战争
Everyone was at war in those years.
但他是在塞萨洛尼基
But he was in Thessaloniki.
在最高统帅部
At the supreme command.
- 真的？- 是的
- Really? - Yes.
他后来可能过的不好，所以他发疯了
He probably didn't get along afterwards, so he went crazy.
朱巴！来看这个
Ljuba! Come here, please.
- 你觉得这像什么? - 什么？
- What does this look like to you? - What?
这个
This.
也许是通往竖井的入口
Maybe it could be the entrance to the shaft.
- 通向竖井? - 是的
- To the shaft? - Yes.
那里曾经有银矿
There used to be silver mines there.
那个日尔诺夫就像块瑞士奶酪，你们去普尔沙吗？
That Zhrnov is like Swiss cheese. You're going to Prsha?
- 我们会去的 - 再见！
- We'll come. - See you!
再见！
Bye!
我们走吗？
Are we going?
走
Yes.
但是是去日尔诺夫
But to Zhrnov.
电梯
ELEVATOR
先生，早餐在哪里？
Sir, where do you serve breakfast?
- 这边请，先生 - 谢谢
- This way, sir. - Thanks.
塞尔维亚王子旅馆
HOTEL SERBIAN PRINCE
诺维奇伯爵？
Count Nowicki?
什么事？
Yes?
请跟我们来
Please come with us.
这是什么意思... 你是谁？
What is this supposed to mean... Who are you?
伯爵... 请过来，别惹麻烦
Count... come, please. Don't make trouble.
去散步了，伯爵？
Went for a morning walk, Count?
你是谁? 你要带我去哪儿？
Who are you? Where are you taking me?
亲爱的伯爵，没有理由不高兴
There is no reason to be upset, dear Count.
我是佩塔尔 · 日瓦科维奇
I am Petar Zhivkovich,
国王卫队的首领
the head of the King's Guard.
我听说过你
I've heard about you.
我还从没听说过你，直到现在
And I haven't about you. Until now.
那是什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
你为什么要拜访殿下？
Why are you visiting His Royal Highness?
你不知道吗？
Don't you know?
他们告诉我你是南斯拉夫情报最多的人
They told me that you were most informed man in Yugoslavia.
我要确定一些
I am going to establish some details
外交部长巴尔图访问贵国的细节
of Foreign Minister Bartu's visit to your country.
仅此而已
That is all.
从什么时候开始，这种访问的礼节就成了第五局的事了？
Since when is the protocol of such visit a matter for the Fifth Bureau?
这个问题最好还是问问殿下，不是吗？
It seems to be better to ask His Highness about that, doesn't it?
我们认为殿下
You know, we think that Our Highness,
出于对祖国的热爱
out of great love for your country,
要做一些仓促的行动
would be ready for hasty moves,
比如承认苏联主权
such as the recognition of the Soviet Union, for example.
部长大人，大家都认为
Your minister, who everyone thinks
他将是法国未来的总理
is the future prime minister of France,
已经有一段时间了
has been working on it for a while.
够了
That's enough.
我来这里不是为了和你讨论我国的政治
I didn't come here to discuss the politics of my country with you.
但是你却来干涉我国的政治
But you have come to interfere in the politics of my country.
亲爱的先生，南斯拉夫正处于危急关头
Dear sir, Yugoslavia is on the razor's edge,
这样的举动对我们来说是灾难
such a move would be disastrous for us.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我现在可以下车了吗? 还是说我被捕了？
May I go out now? Or am I under arrest?
不，当然不是
No, of course not.
停车
Stop.
我们会照顾你的
We will take care of you.
这是兔子毛吗？
Is that rabbit?
不，是狼
No, wolf.
可怜的狼
Poor wolf.
- 日瓦科维奇先生？- 什么事？
- Mr. Zhivkovich? - Yes?
你要知道你不是唯一担心的人
You need to know that you are not the only one worried.
再见
Goodbye.
- 去哪儿？- 去纪念碑
- Where? - To the monument.
不允许
Not allowed.
- 为什么？- 这是命令
- But why? - That's the order.
从现在开始，这个区域禁止进入
From now on, access to the location is prohibited.
不仅公众是禁止进入，警察也是如此
It is forbidden for the public, even for the police.
我们必须完成调查
We have to finish the investigation.
去城里完成
Finish it in the city.
我们是贝尔格莱德警察
We are the Belgrade police.
你聋了吗？不能进
Are you deaf? No way!
- 怎么回事？ - 他们想进来
- What's going on? - They want to enter.
叫他们去死吧！
Tell them to go to hell!
- 快点！走开！- 斯坦尼萨夫列维奇上校！
- Come on! Go away! - Colonel Stanisavljevic!
你意识到你严重妨碍调查了吗？
Are you aware that you're seriously obstructing the investigation?
我在妨碍你的调查？
I'm obstructing your investigation?!
听着，孩子，那个案子已经结了
Listen, kid, that case is closed.
如果有些事情你不清楚，问问你的领导
And if something is not clear to you, ask your boss.
他叫什么来着...
What was his name...
耶雷米奇！去问他！
Jeremic! Ask him!
滚出我的视线
Get out of my sight.
- 滚！- 我们走
- Go away! - Let's go.
快点！
Come on!
波兹达！走了！
Bozidar! Come on!
你明白我们要拆除什么吗？
Do you understand what needs to be demolished?
真是个可恶的人
What an awful man.
我们走
Let's go.
来吧! 下注！
Come on! Taking bets!
在赞内身上下注？为什么? 他很瘦，什么都做不了
Betting on Tzane?! What for? He's skinny, can't do anything.
这是给另一个人的钱！
Here's the money for the other one!
停! 如果我在另一个人上下注，我会得到钱吗？
Stop! If I bet on the other one, will I get the money?
你觉得呢？当然了！
What do you think?! Well, of course!
他们来了！
Here they are!
嘿，兄弟！你好吗？
Hey, pal! How are you?
还行
Fine.
好的，把战士带来了吗？
Okay. Brought the fighters?
我肯定不是来这里过除夕的
I certainly didn't come to spend New Year's Eve here.
好吧，我想他可能害怕了
Okay. I thought he might be scared.
当然，拉尔! 过来！
Sure. Lale! Come here!
等等...等等
Wait, wait.
这位是拉尔 · 博扎兹加，枪支贫民窟的冠军
This is Lale Bozadzija. The champion of the Gun slum.
天啊... 他们从哪儿找到他的？
Jesus... Where did they get him?
天啊... 这是什么? ！
Oh, God... What's this?!
我们完蛋了
We're screwed.
我要押博扎兹加！
My money for Bozadzija!
小心脚下
Watch your step.
到了
There you go.
你先请
After you.
- 索尔达托维奇先生 - 晚上好
- Mr. Soldatovich. - Good evening.
萨夫科维奇先生，一切都准备好了
Mr. Savkovich, everything is ready.
你们终于来了
You came, finally.
我差点因为等你而死
I almost died waiting for you.
安东先生，”普里扎德”
Mr. Anton, "Prizad",
是一个由我领导的
headed by me is a happy combination
国家和私人倡议之间的美妙组合
between the state and a private initiative.
我可以给你马其顿最好的鸦片
So, I offer you Macedonian opium of the highest quality,
我控制着一切
I control everything;
从生产到运输，再到机构
from production, through transport, to institutions.
换句话说，我没有竞争对手
In other words, I have no competition.
真厉害
Impressive.
非常厉害
Very impressive.
特别是当米里奇先生用甜言蜜语的方式解释的时候
Especially when Mr. Mirich explains it with his sweet-talking style.
但是你在这里是很重要的
But it is important that you are here
你们可以互相帮助
and that you can help each other.
因此对我们所有人来说
And therefore to all of us.
戈迪纳先生在芝加哥有非凡的关系网
Mr. Godina has remarkable connections in Chicago.
是的，我听说了
Yes, I heard about that.
- 你听说了什么？- 这位卡彭先生
- What have you heard? - That Mr. Capone here,
是一个非常值得尊敬的人
is a very respectable person.
对我来说，能和这样一个体面的组织一起工作是一件非常愉快的事情
It will be a great pleasure for me to work with such a respectable family.
我希望你们
And I hope that your cooperation,
和那个卡罗老板还有哈吉 · 阿尔索夫等等
with those Macedonian bandits
那些马其顿土匪的合作能够停止
with a certain boss Kyro and that sick Hadzi Arsov will stop.
会结束的
It will be over.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
- 我保证 - 太好了
- I guarantee. - Great.
我们的警官来了！
Here are our inspectors!
来吧! 坐下！
Come on! Take a seat!
军队中断了我们在日尔诺夫的调查
They interrupted our investigation in Zhrnov.
那是军事事务
It's a military thing.
坐下! 普尔莎，过来！
Take a seat! Prsha, come here!
我们必须回到日尔诺夫
We have to go back to Zhrnov.
哦，去他妈的日尔诺夫! 坐下，这是命令! 普尔莎！
Oh, fuck Zhrnov! Sit, it's an order! Prsha!
不要因为一杯酒就让我逮捕你！
Don't make me arrest you because of a drink!
来了！
It's coming!
- 新年快乐! - 谢谢！
- Happy New Year! - Thanks!
给你普莱蒂科西奇，你怎么了？
Here you go, Pletikosa. What?!
我很好，谢谢
I'm good, thanks.
现在怎么办? 我们要放弃吗？
Now what? We're giving up?
也许局长是对的，今天是除夕夜
Maybe the chief is right. It's the New Years Eve.
我们明天再考虑
We'll think about it tomorrow.
你今晚要出去参加聚会吗？
Are you going out for a party tonight?
如果你想的话，我们可以去别的地方
If you're in the mood, we can go somewhere.
没心情
I don't feel like it.
那个日尔诺夫真让我心烦
That Zhrnov is bothering me.
保重伙计
Take care, pal.
- 警官！ - 什么事？
- Inspector! - Yes?
新年快乐！
Happy New Year!
谢谢，你也是
Thanks. You, too.
- 晚上好，伯爵先生 - 晚上好
- Good evening, Mr. Count. - Good evening.
我们走
Let's go.
告诉我，这个叫拉尔的家伙，他只会摆姿势吗？
Tell me, this guy Lale, he makes bozas?
不，他是个小偷，那只是他的绰号
No, he is a thief. It's just his nickname.
我的孩子不笨，但他是一个很好的战士
My boy is not stupid but he is a very good fighter.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
你在哪儿找到他的？在苏尔杜利察吗？
Where did you find him, in Surdulica?
什么? ！
What?!
我听说他们用石头打自己，只是为了好玩
I heard they beat themselves there with a stone, just for fun.
这孩子出生在贝尔格莱德
The kid was born in Belgrade.
拜托！
Oh, come on!
找一个没被干过的妓女都比
It is easier to find a whore who isn't fucked,
在亚塔汗贫民窟找一个贝尔格莱德人更容易
than a man from Belgrade in Yataghan slum.
为什么叫枪支贫民窟？
Why is it called the Gun slum?
你为什么这么在乎？
Why do you care?
只是问问，我以为你们都有小枪
Just asking. I thought you have small guns.
- 老大! 他不在这儿！- 谁？
- Boss! He's not here! - Who?
- 迪塞尔! 我们找不到他! - 迪塞尔不见了？
- Diesel! We can't find him! - The Diesel is gone?
是的，他不见了
Yes. He's gone.
在这呢
There he is.
该死! 你这辈子见过女人吗？
Damn it! Have you ever seen a cunt in your life?
你非得每天都这样吗！
Do you have to do it every day?!
你今晚有一场拳击比赛！
You have a boxing match tonight!
他整个下午都在跟我打拳击
He's boxing me all afternoon.
闭嘴，婊子
Shut up, bitch.
米兰，我只是..
Milan, I was just...
你只是在和布兰卡上床！
You were just fucking Branka!
- 你射了吗? - 什么? ！
- Did you cum? - What?!
你射出来了吗? 射了吗？
Are you done? Did you cum?
- 没有 - 太好了！
- No. - Great!
你已经准备好去打博扎兹加了，跟我来！
You're ready for Bozadzija. Come with me!
全押！
Pot!
不跟
No!
我跟！
Repot!
我付钱
I'm paying.
怎么可能? 你都破产了
How? You're totally broke.
把钱拿出来，否则你就完了
Take the money out or you're done.
我保证我会付钱给你
I guarantee I will pay you.
你们提供什么作为保证？
What do you give as a guarantee?
我想宪法法院的法官
I guess the word of a judge
说的话是有些其分量的
of the Constitutional Court has its weight.
也许在法庭上有分量，但在这里没用
Maybe in the courtroom. Here, you can stick it up your ass.
迪米特里耶维奇先生，我能指望你的小小帮助吗？
Mr. Dimitriyevich, can I count on your little help?
什么样的帮助？
What kind of help?
一些赌场信用
Some credit, on the house.
这不是银行，这是非法赌场
This is not a bank, this is an illegal casino.
是的，但我会连本带利把钱还给你
Yes, but I will return that money to you with interest.
没门！
Fuck off!
你已经深陷债务
You're head over heels in debt.
如果你没有钱就别玩了
If you have no money, give up.
我会借钱给这位先生
I'll lend this gentleman the money.
等等，你不能就这样做，游戏还没结束
Wait, you can't do it just like that, in the middle of a the game!
是谁决定的呢？
And who determines that?
我
Me.
听着，年轻人，我不知道你是谁，我也不在乎
Listen, young man, I don't know who you are, and I don't care.
但是你不能制定规则，这是肯定的
But you will not set the rules. That's for sure.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
你他妈的凭什么跟我说这些？
And who the fuck are you to tell me that?
你最好不要知道我是谁
It's better for you to never know who I am.
好吧，好吧
Well, well...
你在威胁我吗？
Are you threatening me?
你他妈的在耍我吗? ! 离我远点，混蛋！
You're fucking around, huh?! Get away from me, motherfucker!
滚，我没跟你说话！
Go away, I didn't ask you anything!
好吧，好吧
Okay, okay...
如果你借钱给他
If you lend him money,
我就把你的胳膊扯下来
I'll rip your arm off.
- 不会有人的胳膊被扯下来 - 为什么？
- There won't be ripping arms. - Why?! Why?!
悠着点，米兰
Easy, Milan.
你们看我还年轻，所以可以做任何你想做的事，嗯？
You saw that I was young, so you can do whatever you want, huh?
放轻松
Take it easy.
米兰，喝杯酒
Milan, here's a drink.
什么酒，你这个婊子? ！
What drink, you bitch?!
滚出去！
Get the hell outta here!
到了
Here.
- 就在这里 - 是的
- So it's here. - Yes, here.
在入口处介绍你自己
Introduce yourself at the entrance.
明天10点会议结束后我会等你
I will be waiting for you tomorrow after the meeting at 10.
很好
Good.
- 伯爵先生... - 什么事？
- Mr. Count... - Yes?
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
魔法莉莉奇妙的幻觉世界
MAGIC LILLY WONDERFUL WORLD OF ILLUSION
- 晚上好! - 晚上好，尼娜！
- Good evening! - Good evening, Nina!
欢迎! 您的桌子已经准备好了
Welcome! Your table is ready.
- 比去年好多了 - 我们已经尽力了
- It's better than last year. - We're doing our best.
只有这种轻音乐吗，还是会有传统音乐？
Just this light music or it's gonna be something traditional?
那将会是..
It will be...
我们有一个特别的惊喜
And we have a special surprise.
真的吗，什么？
Really, what?
如果我告诉你，就不是惊喜了
If I tell you, it won't be a surprise.
你为什么关心这个惊喜？
Why do you care about the surprise?
- 我很关心 - 好好享受今晚吧
- I do. - All right, enjoy the evening.
你已经开始喝酒了？
You've already started drinking?
- 你要禁止我喝酒吗? - 你喜欢我禁止吗？
- Will you forbid me? - Would you like it?
- 部长，晚上好 - 晚上好，上校
- Minister, good evening. - Good evening, Colonel.
农业发展如何？
How is agriculture going?
今年是干旱的一年，但会好起来的，干杯！
This year is a drought but it will be better. Cheers!
晚上好，有什么事吗？
Good evening, what can I do for you?
晚上好，夫人，你会说法语吗？
Good evening ma'am, do you speak French perhaps?
当然
Of course.
我的名字叫诺维奇
My name is Nowicki.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
跟我来
Follow me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 请在这里等我 - 乐意之至
- Wait for me here, please. - Gladly.
我会回来找你的
I'm coming back for you.
非常好的地方
Extremely nice place.
这让我想起了柏林的一个俱乐部
It reminds me of a club in Berlin.
真的吗？
Really?
- 达维多维奇夫人! 晚上好! - 夫人
- Mrs. Davidovich! Good evening! - Madam.
我为你准备了特别的惊喜，我们走吧！
I am waiting for you with special pleasure. Let's go!
为你准备了一间包间
A private dining room is ready for you.
来吧
Come.
你不会在争取新闻自由的斗争中获胜
You will not win the fight for freedom of the press.
不，我认为这场战斗会持续很长时间，但我们最终会赢
No, I think the fight will be long, but we will win in the end.
亲爱的! 终于来了！
My dear! Finally!
终于见面了，这是我的丈夫！
To finally meet. This is my husband!
我的荣幸
It's my honour.
久仰大名
I've heard so much about you.
玛雅！
Maya!
很高兴今晚有你们的到来
It is a great pleasure to have you with us tonight.
真是莫大的荣幸
It's a great honour.
这是我丈夫
This is my husband.
阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇
Alimpiye Mirich.
克劳斯 · 冯 · 海涅曼，很高兴见到你
Klaus von Heinemann. Nice to meet you.
亲爱的，让我给你介绍一下
Honey, let me introduce you.
米里奇先生是... 我该怎么说呢？
Mr. Mirich is... What would I call it?
- 一个生意人 - 就这么说吧
- A businessman. - Let's say.
米里奇先生是一位商人
Mr. Mirich is, among other things, a businessman.
这个国家最成功的商人之一
One of the most successful in the country.
非常感谢
Thanks a lot.
- 你在奉承我，玛雅 - 我不是故意的
- You're flattering me, Maya. - I didn't mean to.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
来吧，我们坐下来！
Come on! Let's take a seat!
请给先生们来一杯香槟！
One champagne for gentlemen, please!
女士们先生们！
Ladies and gentlemen!
新年即将到来！
New year is coming tonight!
我向大家介绍我们第一场争夺冠军头衔的拳击比赛！
I present you our first boxing match for the championship title!
在我的左边
On my left,
是一个体重135公斤的人
a man who weighs 135kg,
来自枪支贫民窟的拉尔 · 博扎兹加！
Lale Bozadzija from The Gun slum!
现在... 在我的右边
And now... On my right,
一个体重75公斤的人
a man who weighs 75kg,
来自亚塔汉贫民窟的不败冠军
undefeated champion from Yataghan slum
帅气的迪塞尔！
Pretty Tzane named Diesel!
十块钱押我儿子！
Ten bucks for my son!
你看到那家伙有多大了吗？
Do you see how big this guy is?
- 那押20吧！- 亲爱的上帝..
- Make it twenty! - Dear Lord...
快点，猪肉要凉了
Hurry up, the pork is getting cold.
打不过就跑！
If it becomes intense, run away no matter what!
什么比生命更重要？
What's bigger than life?
还有什么比死亡更重要？
And what's bigger than death?
幻觉
An illusion.
我们可以欺骗自己说我们真的活着
We can lie to ourselves that we really live
但我们真的会死吗？
but do we really die?
因为... 生与死都是骗局
Because... both life and death are just deceptions,
幽灵，鬼魂
apparitions, ghosts.
谁在另一边？
Who is on the other side?
在那里等待我们的是什么？
And what awaits us there?
让你的声音被倾听
Let your voice be heard,
我们今晚在这里
and we're here tonight,
因为，感谢上帝，我们还活着
because, thank God, there are us.
如果你不和我们在一起
If you are not with us,
你不必也不应该这样
you don't have to and shouldn't be.
但是你要知道
But just so you know,
明天这个世界就是我们的了！
tomorrow this world will be ours!
等等! 听着！
Wait! Listen!
战斗必须公平！不准有任何吉普赛巫术
The fight must be fair! Without any gipsy shit.
还有一件事...
And one more thing. This is how we're gonna do this.
加油! 加油！
Come on! Come on!
你真可爱！
You're so cute!
快点! 动起来！
Come on! Move a bit, move!
谁在那儿? ！
Who's there?!
跟我来！
Follow me!
你不会后悔的！
And you won't regret!
也许你会！
Or maybe you will!
上帝啊！
Jesus Christ!
我们即将进入新的一年
We are entering the new year soon.
新的幻觉
The new illusion.
别担心，一切都会恢复正常的
Don't worry, everything will be the same.
但...有所不同
And yet... different.
十！
Ten!
九！
Nine!
八！
Eight!
- 达维多维奇夫人！- 七！
- Mrs. Davidovich! - Seven!
六！
Six!
五！
Five!
四！
Four!
三！
Three!
二！
Two!
一！
One!
诺维奇伯爵，坐下
Count Nowicki. Sit down.
谢谢
Thanks.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.